Personal Details

Name: Mona Bakri. Material Status: Single. Visa Status: Family Visa.

Contact Number: +96596717420/+96566597600

Email: mona-bakri@hotmail.com

Objective

I'm a network security engineer with 3 years and 6 months of experience in providing solutions, implementation, configuration and troubleshooting of Cisco Routers and switches, firewalls, fine tuning firewalls, VPN configuration, troubleshooting network related problems in enterprise network. I am very energetic person dedicated to my work and keen to improve myself and to learn more and more. I like to work in healthy atmosphere and I am friendly to my surrounding persons.

Skills

- Teamwork
- Communication skills
- Flexibility
- Quick Learner
- Attention to details
- TCP/IP Networking
- Network Security
- CCNA and CCNP (R&S)
- Network Administration
- Visual Basic and Edraw Max

- Troubleshooting
- Fortinet products (FortiGate, FortiWeb, FortiMail, FortiAP, FortiAnalyzer and FortiSIEM)
- GateProtect
- Watchguard
- Sophos Firewall
- OPManager
- VOIP
- Technical Support
 - PRTG Monitoring System

Experience

Advocates Group Academy

IT Manager

- Configure Viewboard.
- Configure IP phones.
- Monitor and maintenance network.
- Secure the infrastructure.
- Troubleshoot the Microsoft office problems.
- Install windows 11.
- Write documentation.
- Network administration
- Configure and Add employee to attendance management system (ZK Tech).
- Request to buy devices related to IT field.
- Create QR code for trainee certificate.
- Technical Support.
- Kiosk for devices.

Usetek Co. Ltd

10/2020 - 11/2021

IT Security Engineer

- Provided support for 85% of sudan's most reputable banks and financial institutions.
- Provide support for ministries in Sudan.
- Network planning, designing, administration and troubleshooting.

08/2022-present

- IP addressing design
- Installation networks with different topologies.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting gateprotect, FortiGate, FortiMail, FortiAP, FortiAnalyzer, FortiSIEM and watchguard
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting VOIP devices.
- Configuration of Layer 2 and multi-layer Cisco switches.
- Installing and configuring virtualization software such as VMware Esxi.
- IPS/IDS.
- proxy (HTTP/HTTPS/SMTP)
- Penetration tests and Vulnerability assessment. Installing, managing, tracking, monitoring, analysing and reporting by using OPManager.

• SHABAKKAT 03/2019 - 05/2019 OMC

Monitoring and maintaining the access network through network management system

- □ (24×7).
- Providing accurate status of alarms and fault through (SMS, email or Phone) to customers, cluster leader and managers.
- Handled alarm monitoring and taking corrective action on any critical situation.
- Analysing network related problems and troubleshooting.
- Examined and located network availability and prepared the sign-off report
 Accountable for configuration management and extending technical support to BSS/Field
 Engineer.

• Vision Valley 12/12018 - 03/2019

Network Engineer (Trainee)

Installation and configuration of CISCO IT infrastructure (CISCO Switches, routers and

- network protocols).
- Solid understanding of Ethernet based networking concepts.
- Proficient in the creation, configuring and troubleshooting of VLAN's and switch trunks.
 Installing and managing UNIX/Linux servers and windows server 2012/2016 XP/7/8/10
- clients.
- Configuring disks, hardware RAID on application Servers.
- Installing, maintaining and Troubleshooting VOIP networks.
- Performing hardware maintenance for Network devices, storage, computers and servers
- Installing and managing Centos.

• Vision Valley
Network Engineer (Trainee)

09/2016 - 12/2016

,

Sudatel Telecomm. Group Ltd

03/2014 - 03/2015

Network Engineer in corporate back office-Network operation centre

- Allocation, implementation, configuration, activation and testing of specific services to meet customer requirements.
- Respond immediately to customer-affecting service problems or failure in order to minimize their effect on customers, and to invoke the restoration of the service, or provide an alternate service as soon as possible (participate in 24x7 call-out if required).

- Managing, tracking, monitoring, analysing, improving and reporting on the performance
- of specific services (monitoring and management of DSLAm, IPBB, Core switches, ports utilization, and traffic utilization).
- Establish, manage and administer the enterprise's service inventory, as embodied in the service Inventory Database, and monitor and report on the usage and access to the service inventory, and the quality of the data maintained in it.
 - Allocation, installation, configuration, activation and testing of specific resources to meet
- the service requirements, and to alleviate specific resource capacity shortfalls, availability concerns or failure condition.
- Liaise with 3rd party suppliers.

Sudan University of Science and Technology

Teacher Assistant
Faculty of Electronics Engineering

Education

- University of Medical Science and Technology Bachelor of Science Degree in Electronics Engineering/Communication First Class
- Sudan University of Science and Technology
 Master's degree in Electronics and Communication Engineering
 V.good

Technical Certification

CCNA Routing and Switching

Courses

- CCNP Routing and Switching
- GateProtect
- NSE4
- FortiMail
- FortiWeb
- FortiAnalyzer
- Yeastar VOIP

PUBLICATIONS

Articles

[1] Mona Bakri Hassan, Sameer Alsharif, Hesham Alhumyani *et al.* An Enhanced Cooperative Communication Scheme for Physical Uplink Shared Channel in NB-IoT. *Wireless Pers Commun* **120**, 2367–2386 (2021). https://doi.org/10.1007/s11277-021-08067-1

[2] Elmustafa Sayed Ali, Mohammad Kamrul Hasan, Rosilah Hassan, Rashid A. Saeed, Mona Bakri Hassan, Shayla Islam, Nazmus Shaker Nafi, Savitri Bevinakoppa, "Machine Learning Technologies for Secure Vehicular Communication in Internet of Vehicles: Recent Advances and Applications", Security and Communication

09/2013 - 06/2014

Book chapters

- [1] **Mona Bakri Hassan,** Elmustafa Syaed Ali, Rashid A. Saeed, Machine Learning for Industrial IoT Systems. In J. Zhao, & V. Kumar (Ed.), Handbook of Research on Innovations and Applications of Al, IoT, and Cognitive Technologies (pp. 336-358) (2021).. IGI Global. http://doi:10.4018/978-1-7998-6870-5.ch023
- [2] Elmustafa Syaed Ali, Mohammed, Z. T., **Mona Bakri Hassan**, Rashid A. Saeed, Algorithms Optimization for Intelligent IoV Applications. In J. Zhao, & V. Kumar (Ed.), Handbook of Research on Innovations and Applications of Al, IoT, and Cognitive Technologies (pp. 1-25). IGI Global (2021). http://doi:10.4018/978-1-7998-6870-5.ch001
- [3] Elmustafa Sayed Ali Ahmed, **Mona Bakri Hassan**, Rashid Saeed, Terahertz Communication Channel Characteristics and Measurements, In book: Next Generation Wireless Terahertz Communication Networks, CRC Press 2021
- [4] Mona Bakri Hassan, Elmustafa Sayed Ali Ahmed, Rashid A. Saeed, Ultra-Massive MIMO in THz Communications, In book: Next Generation Wireless Terahertz Communication Networks, CRC Press 2021
- [5] Elmustafa Sayed Ali Ahmed, **Mona Bakri Hassan**, Rashid A. Saeed, (2021) Machine Learning Technologies in Internet of Vehicles. In: Magaia N., Mastorakis G., Mavromoustakis C., Pallis E., Markakis E.K. (eds) Intelligent Technologies for Internet of Vehicles. Internet of Things (Technology, Communications and Computing). Springer, Cham. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-76493-7_7
- **[6] Mona Bakri Hassan;** Elmustafa Sayed Ali; **Nahla** Nurelmadina; **Rashid** A. Saeed, **Artificial** intelligence in IoT and its applications, in book: Intelligent Wireless Communications, IET 2021
- [7] Mona Bakri Hassan; Elmustafa Sayed Ali; Rashid A. Saeed, Intelligent Internet of things in wireless networks, in book: Intelligent Wireless Communications, IET 2021.

Language

- English (Professional).
- Arabic (Native).